Daehwa Kim

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, exploring a seamless integration of a computer and human that makes new and pleasant experiences. My prior research lies in (a) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs and (b) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

Sensing Techniques	novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs	sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device
for Fluid Interfaces	AtaTouch (Cond. Accepted CHI'21) +MagTouch (CHI'20)	OddEyeCam (UIST'20)OmniSense (Ongoing)

EDUCATION

KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021 (Expected)

- M.S. student at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
 - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
 - Focus: Sensing Techniques
 - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)
 - o Thesis Committee: Geehyuk Lee (Chair), Juho Kim, Uichin Lee

UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
 - B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
 - Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
 - Entered with top honors.
 - · Graduated with Magna Cum Laude
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCES

- [1] Daehwa Kim, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" To Appear in Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper, To Appear) Honorable Mention Award
- [2] Daehwa Kim, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [3] Keunwoo Park, Daehwa Kim, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings* of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

RESEARCH **EXPERIENCE**

HCI Lab, KAIST

Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

- Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
- Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
- · Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping

Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

- Research Intern, IoT Research Division
 - Project: Smart Home project Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice
 - · Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim
 - Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing

iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST

- Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering

 - · Project: Finger Joystick Interaction
 - Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

 $\bullet\,$ Focus: human-computer interaction, visualization

AWARDS &	Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing	Feb 2021	
SCHOLARSHIPS	■ Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction		
	Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"	OII	
	4th Prize , NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award	Dec 2017	
	■ Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction".	Bee 2017	
	Awarded by NAVER CEO.		
	Received an award of 1,000,000 KRW.		
	Excellence Award , World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016	Dec 2016	
	 Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to university students. Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency. 		
	 Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1. 		
	Dean's List, UNIST		
	■ 2017 Fall Dean's List: GPA 4.05/4.3	Jan 2018	
	■ 2017 Spring Dean's List: GPA 3.98/4.3	Jul 2017	
	 2016 Fall Dean's List: GPA 3.90/4.3 	Feb 2016	
	■ 2016 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.06/4.3	Aug 2016	
	 2015 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.00/4.3 	Jul 2015	
	Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST	Mar 2015 – Feb 2019	
	Entered with top honors.		
	■ Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester.		
	Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST	Jun 2018	
	• Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London		
TEACHING	Teaching Assistant, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNIST	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018	
EXPERIENCE	Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNIST	Feb 2017 – Dec 2017	
	Instructor, Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT)	Jul 2016 – Sep 2016	
	■ Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016	-	
ACADEMIC	Reviewer		
SERVICE	■ CHI '21 LBW		
CAMPUS	D2 factory, NAVER		
ACTIVITIES	■ Campus Partner	Feb 2016 – Feb 2017	
	Hosted the 2nd Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE HAVA (Hadron's a Navistary Academy), HINIST. HOWAND AND AND AND AND AND AND AND AND AND		
	HeXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST		
	• A computer security & development research group	E-1-2016 E-1-2017	
	■ Vice-President	Feb 2016 – Feb 2017	
	 Head of Android development team Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members 	Feb 2017 – Dec 2017	
	UNIST Media Center, UNIST		
	■ Video Editor	Mar 2015 – Feb 2017	
	■ Representative work	17101 2010 1 60 2017	
	My Age 22 - Travel to Europe with a drone		
	Web drama: The town where engineers live		
PROJECTS	Audio Hero	Sep 2019 – Dec 2019	
	 Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model 	•	
	 Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing 		
	VRone	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018	
	 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone 		
	 Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming 		
	System Light 2.0 @ ETRI	Jan 2018 – Mar 2018	
	Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights		
	 Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing 		

VibCat Oct 2017 – Dec 2017

- Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction
- Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Finger joystick interaction

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

- Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen
- Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Poem a moment Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

- An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper
- Available on Google Play store (download 1000+)
- Skills: Android programming

TUIT Android Lecture

Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

- Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students
- Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming

Mr.Bill Jun 2016 – Jul 2016

- Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way
- Available on Google Play store (download 500+)
- Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2021-03-15 for Acme Corporation]